22 years inside a modern cult
Holy Hell is a documentary film directed by Will Allen.
An inside look at a West Hollywood cult formed by a charismatic
teacher in the 1980s that eventually imploded.
Himself, played by Will Allen.
Holy Hell is a 2016 American documentary film by Will Allen about his
experiences as a member of the Buddhafield cult for 22 years.
The cult's leader, who has several names but is typically called
Michel, is claimed to have abused his followers.
The film uses footage Allen shot during his capacity as the group's videographer and new
footage of interviews with former members and of the group in Hawaii.
The film premiered on January 25, 2016 at the 2016 Sundance Film
Festival and saw a limited theatrical release in May 2016.
It was picked up for broadcast by CNN and aired on September 1, 2016.
It was selected for competition at the Sundance Film Festival.